Finding Aid for the Adelbert Bartlett Papers LSC.1300
UCLA Library Special Collections
- California
  - Santa Monica - Malibu
    - Santa Monica and Santa Barbara posed photos, Negatives. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Santa Monica and Washington State, newspaper clippings (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Santa Monica City Hall, etc. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Santa Monica Geneological Society (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Santa Monica home (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Santa Monica Methodist - Trinity Baptist (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Santa Monica Mountains (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Santa Monica road races - Barney Oldfield (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Santa Monica Theatre Guild, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Production of Mlle. Modiste
    - Santa Monica Theatre Guild (Box 65, Folder 18)
      Production of Scarlet Gulch
    - Santa Monica Theatre Guild (Box 65, Folder 19)
      Clips and Programs
    - Santa Monica Theatre Guild (Box 65, Folder 20)
      Miscellaneous productions
    - Santa Monica Theatre Guild (Box 65, Folder 21)
      Productions of The Student Prince and The Pirates of Penzance
    - Santa Monica Theatre Guild. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Various productions
    - Santa Monica., (1957) (Box 55, Folder 6)
      Newspaper clippings of John B. Daniels's History of Santa Monica. No Bartlett photo credit
    - Santa Monica-scenics, [2 folders.] (Box 63, Folder 8-9)
    - Topanga - Walter Prier - William Lloyd - York House (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Wedding portrait (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Southern California, People and Places
    - Adelbert Bartlett., 1928 (Box 31)
    - Alice Mason, 1928 (Box 31)
    - Anita Complyna (Box 31)
    - Bartlett family and friends (Box 31)
    - Beverly Warren., 1944 (Box 31)
    - Bible Institute of Los Angeles (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - C.C. Thurber, Director of Near East Relief., 1925 - 1926 (Box 31)
      At the home of Mrs. Howard Huntington, Los Angeles
    - Christmas Party. -- Art Smith, 1948. (Box 31)
    - Esther Pearson., July 1939 (Box 31)
    - Garlock Family Group - Old Pasadena Pioneers, 1890s (Box 31)
    - Jean Bartelmeh., 1940. (Box 31)
      (Became Miss America 1941)
    - L.A. Harbor (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Lily Garner., 1946 (Box 31)
    - Long Beach (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Long Beach - beach (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Long Beach and Venice (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Long Beach pier - auditorium disaster (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Los Angeles - miscellaneous. (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Los Angeles - Wilshire Blvd. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Los Angeles area (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles area (?) not labelled (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Los Angeles County Museum, (8 x 10) (Box 52, Folder 46)
    - Los Angeles factories (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Los Angeles Public Library, 1932 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Los Angeles River flood (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles Times bombing (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Lucille Rickson, movie starlett, 1928 (Box 31)
    - Marie Fenn., 1949 (Box 31)
    - Miramar Hotel. Greek dancers and France D. Moss., 1927, 1928, 1936. (Box 31)
    - Palmdale (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Palos Verdes (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Pasadena - Huntington Library (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Redondo Beach (Box 31)
    - Ruby Northridge of Bakersfield., 1946 (Box 31)
    - San Pedro (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Theatre Guild (Box 31)
      (See box 10, f. 1)
    - Westwood/UCLA (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Whittier Heights (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - William Olvis, tenor (Box 31)
    - Wilson Observatory (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Canada
  - Yukon Territory (Box 22, Folder 77)
- Central Europe
  - Central Europe - miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 5)
- Chile
  - Bullfights by Fred Blum (Box 21, Folder 1)
- China
  - Canton, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Peking, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Shanghai, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Clippings
  - Clippings relating to negatives and prints., 4 leaves. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Cyprus
  - People and sites (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - People and places (Box 49, Folder 17)
- Eastern Europe
  - Bohemia
    - Bohemia (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Panoramic view (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Bulgaria
    - Bulgaria (Box 22, Folder 44, Box 57)
    - Bulgaria - people and sites (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - People, places and monuments (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Sofia (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Sofia - Aerial view of Cathedral Square (Box 31)
    - Sofia - Churches (Box 31)
    - Sofia - General (Box 31)
    - Sofia - King Boris (Box 31)
    - Sofia - people, places,and monuments (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Sofia and Rilla monastery (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Rumania
    - Rumania (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Yugoslavia
    - Miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 22, Folder 35)
- Egypt
  - Cairo (Box 22, Folder 26, Box 35)
  - Cairo, Clippings (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Cairo, [4 folders.] (Box 66, Folder 15-18)
  - Cairo, (oversize) (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Cairo - Churches (Box 31)
  - Cairo - City life (Box 31)
  - Cairo - Mosques (Box 31)
  - Cairo - Nile River (Box 31)
  - Cairo - people, places, and monuments (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Cairo - Pyramids (Box 31)
  - Giza (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Giza, (oversize) (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Heliopolis, Egypt - Mrs C. Shore (Box 31)
- England
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 76)
- Eyze
  - Panoramic view (Box 50, Folder 10)
- Foreign
  - Commercial photographs of European sites (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Europe. Matted photos. (Box 66, Folder 3)
    The Cossack, Chalet Hayden Locken
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 24)
- France
  - Cherbourg (Box 22, Folder 68, Box 53)
  - Cherbourg - General (Box 31)
  - Cherbourg - Harbor (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Nice (Box 22, Folder 67, Box 31)
  - Paris - Adelbert Bartlett in Paris., 1926; 23.2 cms. x 17.8 cms. (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Rochefort (Box 22, Folder 69, Box 53)
  - Sites - people (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Versailles (Box 22, Folder 70, Box 31)
  - Paris
    - Food (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Louvre (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - Monuments and sites (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Newspaper clippings - miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Notre Dame (Box 22, Folder 71)
    - Paris (Box 51, Folder 20, Box 53)
    - Paris - Adelbert Bartlett (Box 31)
    - Paris - City scenes (Box 31)
    - Paris - City scenes (Box 31)
    - Paris - Eiffel Tower (Box 31)
    - Paris - L'Arc de Triomphe (Box 31)
    - Paris - Le Jardin des Tuileries (Box 31)
    - Paris - Notre Dame (Box 31)
    - Paris - The Left Bank (Box 31)
    - Paris - The Louvre (Box 31)
    - Paris - The Panthenon (Box 31)
    - Paris and Nice (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - People (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Sites, [3 folders.] (Box 39, Folder 5-7)
    - Street Scenes (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - Streets (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Tuileries (Box 22, Folder 73)
- Germany
  - Berlin (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Tyrol (Box 22, Folder 42)
- Greece
  - Acro-Corinth (Box 30)
  - Alexandropolis - Dr. R.T. Uhls of Near East Relief (Box 30)
  - Athens (Box 22, Folder 46, Box 53)
  - Athens - Acropolis (Box 30)
  - Athens - Arch of Hadrian (Box 30)
  - Athens - Armenian School (Box 30)
  - Athens - Athens University (Box 30)
  - Athens - Baron von Pesche (Box 30)
    Austrian artist on the slope of the Acropolis
  - Athens - Churches (Box 30)
  - Athens - City life (Box 30)
  - Athens - Delphic dancers (Box 30)
  - Athens - Parthenon (Box 30)
  - Athens - Statue of Lord Byron (Box 30)
  - Athens - The Porch of Maidens (Box 30)
  - Athens - Tower of the Wind (Box 30)
  - Athens, Corfu, and Delphi (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Athens, Syra, and Delphi (Box 52, Folder 49)
  - Cavalla (Box 22, Folder 47, Box 30)
  - Corfu (Box 22, Folder 48, Box 30)
  - Corinth (Box 53, Folder 31)
  - Corinth - Acro (Box 53, Folder 28)
  - Corinth - Adelbert Bartlett (Box 30)
  - Corinth - Children and tourists (Box 30)
  - Corinth - Greek and Roman ruins (Box 30)
  - Cyprus (Box 30)
  - Delos (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Delphi (Box 22, Folder 50, Box 53)
  - Delphi - Country life (Box 30)
  - Delphi - Grave of George Cram Cook (Box 30)
    An American poet who died at Parnassus
  - Delphi - Mount Parnassus (Box 30)
  - Delphi - Ruins (Box 30)
  - Epirus (Box 53, Folder 33)
  - Island of Delos - Adelbert Bartlett (Box 30)
  - Island of Delos - General (Box 30)
  - Island of Rhodes (Box 30)
  - Lemnos (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Oropos (Box 22, Folder 51, Box 30)
  - Research., Newspaper Clippings (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Rhodes (Box 22, Folder 54, Box 53)
  - Ruins, [4 folders.] (Box 36, Folder 12-15)
  - Syra (Box 22, Folder 52, Box 53)
  - Syra - City and harbor (Box 30)
  - Thessaly, (5x7) (Box 52, Folder 53)
  - Thrace (Box 30)
  - Village scenes, [5 folders.] (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
- India
  - Amritsar - Golden Temple (Box 31)
  - Bindrahan (Box 31)
  - Calcutta (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Muttra (Box 31)
- Indonesia
  - Java (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Iraq
  - Babylon (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Babylon (Box 35, Folder 4, Box 49)
  - Babylon - Ishtar Gate, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Babylon., Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Baghdad (Box 22, Folder 29, Box 48)
- Italy
  - Amalfi (Box 22, Folder 62, Box 31)
  - Campania - Positano (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Cities, [3 folders.] (Box 38, Folder 5-7)
  - Ducal palace (campanile) (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Florence (Box 22, Folder 61)
  - Leptis Magna (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Lombardy (Box 31, Box 53, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 57, Box 38)
  - Naples (Box 31, Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Negatives (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings - miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Paestum (Box 31)
  - People (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Pompeii (Box 22, Folder 58, Box 39)
  - Positano (Box 22, Folder 60, Box 31)
  - Rome (Box 22, Folder 59, Box 53)
  - Rome, (5x7) (Box 52, Folder 54)
  - Rome - Appian Way (Box 31)
  - Rome - Arch of Constantine (Box 31)
  - Rome - Arch of Septimus Severus (Box 31)
  - Rome - Arch of Titus (Box 31)
  - Rome - Borghese Park (Box 31)
  - Rome - Colisseum (Box 31)
  - Rome - Mussolini addressing crowd (Box 31)
  - Rome - Ostia (Box 31)
  - Rome - Relief from Leptis Magna (Box 31)
  - Rome - St. Peter's (Box 31)
  - Rome - Temple of Excupius (Box 31)
  - Sites, [4 folders.] (Box 38, Folder 1-4)
  - Sorrento (Box 31, Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Tivoli (Box 31, Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Venice (Box 22, Folder 63, Box 53)
  - Venice - Bridge of Sighs (Box 31)
  - Venice - Church della Salute (Box 31)
  - Venice - Ducal Palace (Box 31)
  - Venice - Grand Canal (Box 31)
  - Venice - miscellaneous, (8x10) (Box 52, Folder 50)
  - Venice - St. Mark's Plaza (Box 31)
  - Venice and Positano (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Vesuvius (Box 50, Folder 2)
- Japan
  - Hakone, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Tokyo, 1919 (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Jerusalem
  - Via Dolorosa (Box 52, Folder 17)
- Jordan
  - Jerash (Box 30, Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Jerash., Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Palmyra (Box 36, Folder 4, Box 53)
- Lebanon
  - Baalbek (Box 30, Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Baalbek, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - Baalbek., Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Beirut (Box 35, Folder 5, Box 52)
  - Beirut, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - Beirut - Adelbert Bartlett (Box 30)
  - Beirut - American University (Box 30)
  - Beirut - Bayard Dodge -- President of American University (Box 30)
  - Beirut - Egyptian and Assyrian relics (Box 30)
  - Beirut - Native life (Box 30)
  - Beirut - people (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Beirut - places (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Beirut - Roman ruins (Box 30)
  - Beirut., Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 12, Box 49)
  - Tyre (Box 36, Folder 11, Box 49)
  - Tyre, Hold Copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 45)
  - Near East Relief
    - Beirut - Near East Relief scenes (Box 30)
- Malaysia
  - Kuala Lumpur (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Mexico
  - Negatives (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Tijuana (Box 16, Folder 7, Box 21)
  - Unidentified photo of man (Box 66, Folder 6)
- Monaco
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 65)
- Near East
  - 3 printers blocks (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Captions for photos (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Clippings with AB photo credit (Box 56, Folder 15, Box 64)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 27, Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous locations (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous mounted photographs (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Near East artifacts., 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Near East children. Asia Minor., 22 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Near East children. Greece., 70 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Near East. Asia Minor., 1925 - 1926.; 31 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Near East. Unidentified photographs, 1925 - 1926.; 16 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Near East. Bartlett, Adelbert. Trip to the Near East., 1925 - 1926; 21 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Negatives (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Non-Near East Relief photographs by Bartlett., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Los Angeles Public Library Murals. (See Box 2, f.14 for ephemera)
  - People, buildings and places (miscellaneous locations) (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Travel background clippings and notes (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Travel Background., Newspaper clippings (Box 66, Folder 11)
    (no Bartlett photocredit)
  - Near East Relief
    - Fund raisers for the Near East Relief., 17 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Advertisements and posters.
    - Fund raisers for the Near East Relief. Golden Rule Dinner., 28 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fund raisers for the Near East Relief. Milk campaign., 17 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fund raisers for the Near East Relief. Transportation., 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Near East Relief organizers., 16 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Near East Relief. Miscellaneous photograph., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Near East Relief. Photo album., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Syria
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 9)
- New York
  - Harbor (Box 50, Folder 13)
- North Africa
  - Algiers (Box 31)
  - Carthage (Box 31)
  - Leptis Magna - General (Box 31)
  - Leptis Magna - Roman ruins (Box 31)
  - Port Said (Box 31)
  - Tunisia
    - Dougga [or Thugga] (Box 31)
- Pacific Islands
  - Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 14)
- Palestine
  - A brief guide to Al-Haram Al-Sharif, Jerusalem (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Acre (Box 35, Folder 1, Box 49)
  - Acre, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Acre., Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Bells of Bethlehem, Copper Plate (Box 34)
  - Bethel (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Capernaum (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Capernaum (Box 51, Folder 4, Box 56)
  - Capernaum, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 29)
  - Cave of Machpelah, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - Dead Sea (Box 35, Folder 10, Box 53)
  - Dead Sea, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 31)
  - Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Galilee (Box 35, Folder 11, Box 56)
  - Galilee, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 30)
  - General (Box 36, Folder 3, Box 53)
  - Gethsemane (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Hebron, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 32)
  - Jaffa (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Jaffa, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 33)
  - Jericho (Box 51, Folder 6, Box 52)
  - Jericho, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 35)
  - Jerusalem (Box 22, Folder 30, Box 35)
  - Jerusalem, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 34)
  - Jerusalem, (5x7) (Box 52, Folder 57)
  - Jerusalem - miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Jerusalem - places (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Jordan (Box 35, Folder 21, Box 54)
  - Jordan, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 36-37)
  - Megiddo (Box 36, Folder 1, Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Mount Carmel (Box 51, Folder 10, Box 66)
  - Nazareth (Box 22, Folder 31, Box 36)
  - Nazareth, (5x7) (Box 52, Folder 55)
  - Nazareth, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 38)
  - Nazareth - people and miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Nazareth - places (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Palestine (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Palmyra, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 39-40)
  - Roman Bridge (Albania), 1927; Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 23)
    photo by Mary Wallace Mein
  - Sebastia (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Sebastia (Samaria) (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Serbia - Nish, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 42)
  - Unidentified photos, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Jordan Valley
    - Acre (Box 30)
    - Baisan (Box 30)
    - Baisan (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Bethany (Box 30, Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Bethany, (5x7) (Box 52, Folder 56)
    - Bethlehem (Box 30, Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Bethlehem, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - Bethlehem - Arab children (Box 30)
      Scope and Contents
      Photographs taken and inscribed to Bartlett by Palestinian photographer Karimeh Abbud.
    - Bethlehem - Church of the Nativity (Box 30)
    - Bethlehem - The road from Jerusalem (Box 30)
    - Bethlehem and miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Canaan (Box 30, Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Canaan., Duplicates (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Dead Sea (Box 30)
    - Enganim (Box 30)
    - Haifa - including Mount Carmel (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - 6th. station at Via Dolorosa (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - British war cemetery (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Church at the Garden of Gethsemane (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Church of the Holy Sepulchre (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Damascus Road (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Dead Sea from the Mount of Olives (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Essex coach on Jaffa Road near the Hotel Allenby (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Kutahi Pottery (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Moslem quarter (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Mosque of Omar, (composite photograph) (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Mount Moriah (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Mount of Olives (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Mount Scopus (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Mount Zion (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Native life (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Near Jaffa Gate -- Citadel in the distance (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Old Third Wall (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Old Town (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Robert Freeman of the Pasadena Presbyterian Church. (Box 30)
      (see also Sidon)
    - Jerusalem - Russian Church (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - St. Stephen's Gate (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Street scenes (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - The Dome of the Rock (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - The Golden Gate (Box 30)
    - Jerusalem - Valley of Kidron -- Absolom's Tomb (Box 30)
    - Jordanian Valley (Box 30)
    - Mount Tabor (Box 30)
    - Nazareth - Church of the crusaders (Box 30)
    - Nazareth - Near East Relief shop (Box 30)
    - Nazareth - Scenes of village life. (Box 30)
      Including the animal market, camels, mosques, children and tourists. Some photographs taken by Palestinian photographer Karimeh Abbud.
    - Ramallah (Box 30, Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Ramallah, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - River Jordan (Box 30, Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Saffourich (Box 30)
    - Samaria (Box 30, Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Samaria - Jacob's Well (Box 52, Folder 58)
    - Sea of Galilee (Box 30)
    - Tiberius (Box 30, Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Tomb of Lazarus (Box 30)
  - Palestine
    - Jericho (Box 35, Folder 20)
- Pennsylvania
  - Philadelphia (Box 21, Folder 13, Box 31)
- Phillipines
  - Manila Bay (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Photo Albums
  - Proof photographs of Europe and the Middle East, 857 items. (Box 9)
  - Proof photographs of the Middle East, 869 items. (Box 8)
  - Proofs of photographs of Palm Springs and other [parts of] CA, 1898-1937; (oversize) (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - United States - California - Long Beach, (oversize) (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - United States - California - Palm Springs, 1935-1937; (oversize) (Box 61, Folder 2)
- Poland
  - Cracow (Box 31)
  - Galacia (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Warsaw Cathedral (destroyed in World War I) (Box 31)
- Russia
  - Baku (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Caucasus (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Moscow (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Nijni Novgorod (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Vladivostock (Box 22, Folder 23)
- Serbia
  - Belgrade (Box 31)
  - General (Box 31)
  - River Danube (Box 31)
- Singapore
  - Singapore (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Spain
  - Alhambra (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 64, Box 48)
- Switzerland
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 66)
- Syria
  - Aleppo (Box 30, Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Boy shepherds of Syria No. 930 - 950 series (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Damascus (Box 30)
    (including bazaar and metal work)
  - Damascus (Box 35, Folder 9, Box 49)
  - General (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Ghanzir (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Hama (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Jebeil (Box 35, Folder 16, Box 49)
  - Jebeil - Crusader and Phoenician ruins (Box 30)
  - Jebeil - Village life (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Places and people (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Sidon (Box 36, Folder 7, Box 52)
  - Sidon, Hold copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 43)
  - Sidon - Adelbert Bartlett (Box 30)
  - Sidon - Armenian children (Box 30)
  - Sidon - Camels (Box 30)
  - Sidon - Crusader and Greek ruins (Box 30)
  - Sidon - Dr. Geo. Alford Ford (Box 30)
  - Sidon - Druse Palace (Box 30)
  - Sidon - people and misc. (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Sidon - places (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Sidon - Reverend Robert Freeman of the Pasadena Presbyterian Church (Box 30)
  - Sidon - Village and country life (Box 30)
  - Syria (Box 54, Folder 6, Box 57)
  - Syria (Syrian Coast), Hold Copies (to be copied) (Box 52, Folder 44)
  - Syrian coast (Box 30)
  - Syrian coast (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Syrian Coast - Places and miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 5)
- Turkey
  - Armenia - General (Box 30)
  - Bakhara - Bazaar (Box 30)
  - Bakhara - General (Box 30)
  - Bakhara - Palace of the Emir (Box 30)
  - Bakhara - Village life (Box 30)
  - Caspian sea town (Box 30)
  - Constantinople (Box 22, Folder 55, Box 40)
  - Constantinople, (5x7) (Box 52, Folder 59)
  - Constantinople - American Women's College (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - American-Jewish Orphanage (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Churches (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - City life (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Golden Horn (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Grand bazaar (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Istamboul (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Mosque of the Sultan Ahmen (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Mosques (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Obelisk of Theodosius (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Ste. Sophia Church (Box 30)
  - Constantinople - Turkish School (Box 30)
  - Istanbul (Box 35, Folder 14, Box 56)
  - Istanbul, (8x10) (Box 52, Folder 51)
  - Samarkand - General (Box 30)
  - Samarkand - Tomb of Tamerlane (Box 30)
  - Sebaste - Crusader ruins (Box 30)
  - Sebaste - General (Box 30)
  - Smyrna (Box 22, Folder 56, Box 36)
  - Tashkent (Box 30)
  - Turkestan (Box 30)
  - Near East Relief
    - Armenia - Near East Relief (Box 30)
- Uzbekistan
  - Bokhara (Box 48, Folder 3)